I hope you're doing well today, Devin.
>> I am. I am. Likewise.
>> Great. Uh, over the past several years,
um, the Panthers leaguewide reputation
remained, uh, near the bottom in NFL PA
player polls, but, uh, Dan Morgan went
out and and signed three of the top uh,
free agents and and made several other
key moves. Number one, what attracted
you to the Panthers? And is the Morgan
Canales culture, is it helping change
the perception players have of the
Panthers franchise?
>> Yeah, absolutely. Um, you know, there's
a lot to, um, be attracted to when it
comes to the team and ultimately that's
why I ended up signing here. Um, I think
there's a lot of great pieces on defense
for one. Um, and obviously being, you
know, a guy, a defender, you know, that
was one thing that I was looking for.
Um, I mean, you got a number of players,
Derek Brown, JC Horn, obviously two most
notable, but, um, you know, Trayvon, um,
I mean, there's guys all over the
defense that make plays and, you know, I
just want to come in and, uh, be a part
of that playmaking unit and help elevate
it the most I can. Um, obviously Dave
Canales, um, you know, I think he's a
great head coach and he's got this team,
um, playing ball the right way. And so
for me, you know, I just want to come in
and, uh, and do my part and help this
team, uh, maximize what we can do.
uh what is the what is the word on the
street so to speak of of the Panthers um
two other players in the league and how
has it changed over the last couple
years?
>> Well, that that all depends on who you
ask, who you talk to. I mean um it could
be different depending on where you ask.
I think um you know
uh I guess it's not something I never
necessarily really focused on. I guess
you could say until I was in free
agency, you know, more so players kind
of focus on their team. Obviously, you
look around and see who's doing what. I
would say um you know, looking at the
Panthers last year from the outside in,
it was a talented team that, you know,
had a lot of really good pieces all over
the place. And I mean, just an ascending
team, you know, you know, Jacksonville
was like that at one point as well. um
just an ascending team and you know
obviously you know made it to the
playoffs, hosted a home playoff game
which is huge and now it's time to take
that next step and so I'm really excited
to be a part of taking that next step.
>> Yeah, I just want to finish up with one
quick hardbiting question. Um who do you
have for the basketball tournament with
it starting today?
>> Oh shoot. I guess we'll just have to
wait and see.
>> You didn't fill out a bracket?
>> No, I did not.
>> Okay. Hey, have a good one. Thanks a
lot.
>> Thank you.
>> Hey K, followed by David Newton.
>> Hey Devin, welcome. Uh, congratulations
on the contract.
>> I was curious, how much did coaching
from scheme to your position coach to
your defensive coordinator help you kind
of reach a career year last season?
>> I mean, I think, you know, when you look
at you talk about coaching, um, coaching
helps develop players. you know,
obviously every player is talented and
they have skill set and now it's on
coaches at all levels, you know, from
high school all the way up to NFL to
really help those players get the most
out of the talent that they have. So, I
mean, you ask me specifically. Yeah. I
mean, I I great I had great coaches last
year and they definitely helped me um
just take a next I say, you know, I give
the most credit to them. They helped me
use my hands. You know, that was one
thing they emphasized and really, you
know, honed in pretty much every day.
Every day at practice, it was use your
hands, use your hands, use your hands.
So, you can play violent, you can play
physical in the run game, shed off
blocks, make plays. That was the thing
that coach Kemp and coach uh Tim Lucaboo
emphasized the most. And uh that's what
I give them the most credit for. And
then um you know scheme wise you know it
comes down to you know no matter where
you're at you know having your players
be in the right position to make the
most plays as possible.
>> And then uh in the passing game
linebackers all have their specialties
but you seem to excel both at both in
coverage and blitzing. How much do you
have to kind of weigh that within your
own game? You know obviously you can
make plays in coverage but you also know
you can get to the quarterback.
Yeah, that just comes down to the
situation, you know. Obviously, um I
think from a coach's lens, you want to
put your playmakers in position and it's
finding the best way to do that.
Obviously, I won't be the only playmaker
on the team. We got playmakers all over
the place. So, for him, it's coach,
it's, you know, how can I get all my
guys going um doing what they're best at
situationally. It's like, okay, you
know, right now it's his time. Okay.
Now, in this next series, we're going to
go um you know, get him going. And just
like offensive coordinator, you know,
trying to get their receivers going or
running backs going, defensive
coordinator, same thing. You got guys
all over the place. So, it's just uh
situationally, you know, and uh calling
in at the right time.
>> Thanks. Thanks, Deon.
>> Hey, Deon. David Newton with ESPN.com.
Welcome to Charlotte.
>> Thank I want to ask you, Luke Forner
asked uh said the other day that you you
were so intense in practice that you had
to tell you to calm down sometimes. Uh
give me an example of that and what's
that say about you?
>> Um specific example on I mean I just go
hard at practice, you know, I really um
you know try to treat practice like the
game as much as I can and obviously
there's there's a time and a place to
you know be physical I guess you could
say. Like I wouldn't necessarily see um
if you're not if you're playing without
pads that that's the most um as that's
the smartest time to be physical, but
you can always play fast. You can always
play with great technique. You always
play um just just flying around the
field really at 100 miles an hour. And I
think that's what he was referring to.
Um
oh, sorry, what was the second part of
your question?
>> Well, that was pretty much it. I wanted
to also ask you too. I mean, the Jaguars
didn't pick up your fifth year option.
Um,
how did that impact you looking
elsewhere and and how things kind of
turned out for you?
>> Yeah, as far as the fifth year option,
um, whenever I found out the news, it
was just more so, okay, like um, at this
point now, I know um, you know, this is
effectively uh, a one-year prov
like like a contract year, I guess you
could say. That's what um, you know, the
term that everybody says. It was more so
just me understanding like, okay, after
this year I'm gonna be a free agent, you
know, especially with the linebacker tag
and it being mixed in with pass rushers.
So, um, you know, I mean, that's just,
you know, the reality of it. You know,
you look at that and you look at it and
you're realistic with yourself. Um, but
other than that, it was just more so
just playing ball. I didn't put too much
into it. At the end of the day, um, I
just went out and attacked each day and,
you know, let the day stack. And what
makes you so good in coverage?
>> Um, I think it's just a natural feel.
You know, you're looking at the
quarterback. You know, a lot of plays I
made in in zone coverage and, um, you
just have a feel for looking at the
quarterback, know where he wants to go.
I think, uh, knowing the route concepts
is huge. So, it's really about getting
to your landmark as quick as possible
and then that allows you to play off the
routes versus, um, you know, I see a lot
of linebackers, what we call drifting.
they're not set, their feet aren't set,
and it doesn't allow them to get their
feet in the uh getting their feet in the
ground and make plays on the ball in the
air. Um so it comes down to technique, a
feel for the game, and ultimately um
when the ball's in the air, it's a
mentality of that's your ball.
>> Appreciate it. Thank you.
>> We'll go with Joe Pson followed by Alex
Zitlo.
>> Hey Devin, it's Joe with the Athletic.
Congrats on the contract.
>> Thank you.
Um, you were asked earlier about kind of
your your versatile skill set and I I
just wondered this ended up being kind
of a a free agency for linebackers where
uh a lot of y'all didn't get what the
so-called experts were projecting. Was
that a surprise to you given all that
you do? like because you know you're not
just a guy playing the run first and
second down.
>> It was um but that's just the way the
market went this year and uh that's what
it was.
And then I know you said you didn't
spend a lot of time obviously when you
were in Jacksonville studying the
Panthers, but over the course of the
last week or maybe even you know in free
agency when you heard they were going to
be interested. Did you dig into this
defense and you know what and what had
your conversations with a Gerald been
like in terms of your role and expanding
your role?
Um, I mean they were brief, uh, but I
know they're excited. Um, just about,
you know, obviously getting me in the
defense, um, getting Jaylen in the
defense and, you know, obviously all the
pieces that we have. So, um, more of
those talks will happen whenever, you
know, we get things going at OTAAS. Um,
right now it's just about getting
settled in Charlotte and um, yeah, I
mean, pretty much that.
>> You and Jaylen were among the top three
free agents any position in a lot of the
rankings, including ours. Um, what was
it like when when you know, you saw him
come here and then a little later in the
day or, you know, I guess into the
evening you you follow him and what what
was your reaction?
>> It was exciting. I mean, you know, he's
a hell of a player. Uh the way he plays
the game, um he's just very aggressive
and uh you know, even my my I've had
coaches that that have talked about him
as well and uh they agree, you know,
they echo the same thing. So, I'm
excited to play with him. Um and like I
said, we have, you know, guys all over
that I'm excited to play with as well.
Um, whenever you look at our defense
and, uh, you know, the things that Dan
was doing and is doing actively with our
team, um, you can't help but, you know,
be optimistic for the future and what
we're going to do on Sundays.
>> Thanks, Devin.
>> Hey, Devin. Alex here with the Charlotte
Observer. Welcome to Charlotte, man.
>> Thank you.
>> Um, I wanted to quickly follow up about
the the question about your fifth year
option. And I understand that you said
that um you didn't put much stock to it.
It wasn't like a thing that made you
hung hungrier so to speak or anything
like that. And I'm curious where does
that I don't know level-headedness come
from?
>> Uh ultimately it stems in in my faith. I
think everything ultimately goes back to
my faith and just um understanding
that's God's plan. You know, it'll never
truly be how you know I envision it. um
it's always going to be how he envisions
it, how it plays out, and um even if
it's whether it goes my way or whether
it doesn't, um I know it's all going to
work out. So, it's just trusting him and
uh day by day uh just accepting what
comes to you. Obviously, attacking each
day and uh from your perspective, from
my perspective, trying to get the most
out of each day, but never not getting
too high, not getting too low on
anything that happens. Uh just trying to
see things from the right lens.
>> Nice. Um, and then I also wanted to ask
about uh your parents were both in the
Navy, correct?
>> Yeah.
>> Um, what I'm just curious how that
impacted you
uh personally and then also in your
football journey.
>> Yeah, the biggest thing with my parents
being in the Navy um is discipline. Um,
just doing all the little things right.
Obviously at home um you know they're
they're pretty strict so you know I
think everything starts at home too.
just all the little things, uh, you
know, cutting the grass on Saturday
mornings, having to get up on your own
to cut the grass or washing cars or
keeping your bathroom and your room
clean, just all the little stuff, doing
your homework, you know, being a good
student. Um, all those things just start
to add up to the point where now it's
um, it's who I am. It's part of my
identity, just being disciplined. And,
um, nobody has to tell me to get up and
and go work out, you know. Um, and over
the years it's built up to, you know,
now it's a part of my lifestyle. So, I'd
say that's the biggest thing.
>> Wonderful. Thanks, man.
>> We have time for a few more. We'll go
with Cass, followed by Sheena.
>> Hey, Devin. How's it going?
>> I'm good. I'm good. How are you doing?
>> Good. Sorry, my camera is not working,
so just use your imagination. Um, real
curious. Just wanted to follow up on
that. Did you ever consider going into
the Navy?
Um, I think uh there was an option at
one point where coming out of high
school, if I didn't go to college, it
would be the Navy, but my head was so
focused and I was so determined on going
to college and playing football. So,
that was never really option for me per
se, but it was always there. It was
always available. Like, that was, I
guess you could say, the plan B. Um, but
for me, there really was no plan B.
Like, that was never anything that I
really wanted to do.
And then what I also really wanted to
ask was Luke Forner talked about facing
you in practice earlier this week and
like how sometimes like he did have to
tell you like dude it's not Sunday. What
was that? What were those reps like from
your perspective facing him and now
you'll get to do it again here?
>> Yeah. I mean shoot I go hard at practice
and you know like I said there's a time
and a place to to be smart, not be as
physical. um be more technical. And I
think over the years you learn, you
know, especially when you're young, it's
like, okay, like I'm trying to get after
I'm trying to make a play and now you're
more considerate, I guess you could say,
your teammates as you um grow over time.
There's a time and a place, but uh yeah,
I go hard at practice. You know, for me,
you know, you got to treat practice as
much as you can, like a game depending
on the situation. And so I'm sure uh
yeah, he has some stories of us going at
it. I mean, you know, he's a linebacker,
I'm a linebacker, he's a center, so we
would have a lot of battles. um you know
so yeah I'm sure he brought that up.
>> Thank you.
>> Hi Devin Sheenaquick on Fox Sports
Radio. How are you doing this afternoon?
>> I'm well. I'm well.
>> Well for starters welcome to Carolina.
Um I know you talked a lot about how
important the lineage of linebackers in
in Carolina you know affected your
decision. Did Dan Morgan and him the GM
being a former linebacker that had
success with this particular franchise,
did that weigh in on your decision at
all? And how were those conversations
with him?
>> Yeah, I mean, that's that's a huge plus.
You know, obviously uh he knows what it
takes, you know, to play uh my position
at a high level in this league and um
just my position in general throughout
his football career. And so that's a
huge plus. And um I think that's why we
connected because I feel like in many
ways we do see the game the same.
>> Um and the second just a follow-up
question on that. I know uh we have
heard about your tenacity and your
intensity for every rep whether it's
game or practice. Um and sometimes you
know there's these narratives that float
around during free agency draft period
or whatever and things like that. Do you
think that
how do you view that? How do you, you
know, get around that and and kind of, I
guess, express who you really are as a
person in addition to the player that
you are on the field when it comes to
shopping around during free agency?
>> Uh, I'm not sure all the way what the
narratives are. I don't really focus too
much on that.
>> Okay, perfect. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> All right, last question. Bashtai,
>> Devin, welcome to Carolina. Just a quick
question. We talked about the fifthear
option. Did Jacksonville express
interest in in bringing you back?
>> Um,
uh, they there was an offer on the
table.
>> That's it.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> All right, Devin, that's all the
questions we have for you today. Thanks
for taking the time to talk to us.
>> All right. Thank you.